networkforgood.org 2019-03-31

# Privacy Policy | Network for Good

### **Introduction**

If you are an individual located in the European Union or the European Economic Area, please visit our [Privacy Policy (EU/EEA)](https://www.networkforgood.com/about/privacy-eu/).

We understand your concerns about safety and security and want to assure you that we make every effort to safeguard your privacy when you make donations through our giving system.  Our mission is to help you support any charity, anywhere online – in a convenient and secure manner.

The information below spells out the privacy and security practices of our for-profit entity Network for Good, Inc., a New York corporation (“Network for Good”, “us”, “our” or “we”) and our nonprofit entity Network for Good, a Delaware nonprofit corporation and donor advised fund (tax ID 68-0480736) (together, “Network for Good”).  This Privacy Policy describes the types of information Network for Good may collect from you or that you may provide when you visit our websites or mobile sites at [www.networkforgood.org](http://www.networkforgood.org/) and [www.networkforgood.com](http://www.networkforgood.com/) (including sub-domains, web pages within this site or any equivalent mirror, replacement, substitute, or backup website), or any other website, mobile site or application that links to this Privacy Policy, accessed via any device, or accessing or using any of our Services (collectively, the “Websites”).  “Services” means any of the Network for Good products or services, e.g., Donor Management, Fundraising Pages, and Fundraising Coach, or any applications, including mobile applications, made available by Network for Good.  The definition of Services does not include “Events Now.”

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, please do not hesitate to [contact us](https://www.networkforgood.com/contact/).  If you do not agree with any of the terms and conditions in this Privacy Policy, please discontinue using the Websites and our Services.

This Privacy Policy is organized into three sections: (1) “General Provisions,” which apply to everyone using or visiting the Websites; (2) “Special Privacy & Security Provisions for Donors,” which apply only to users who make donations through our Websites; and (3) “Special Privacy & Security Provisions for Nonprofits, Customers, and Potential Customers,” which apply specifically to nonprofits who use or consider using our Services.

### **1\. General Provisions**

**Security**

We take reasonable security precautions to protect the personal information that we collect and you provide to us.  We use industry-accepted tools, including technology protocols, to protect against the loss, misuse and unauthorized alteration of the information we collect. Network for Good helps to protect your information by working with our vendors who provide a secure and safe environment for credit card donations. Please remember that the safety and security of your information also depends on you. Where we have given you (or you have chosen) a logon ID or password to access certain services or areas of the Websites, you are responsible for keeping this ID and/or password confidential. We ask that you not share such information with anyone or allow anyone to sign-in using your credentials.

Unfortunately, the transmission of information via the internet is not completely secure. Although we do our best to protect your personal information, we cannot guarantee the security of your personal information transmitted to us. Any transmission of personal information is at your own risk. We are not responsible for circumvention of any privacy settings or security measures we put in place for your protection.

**What Information Do We Collect?**

As discussed in greater detail below, we collect two types of information: _personal information_ you submit to us voluntarily and _information we collect automatically_ when you use our Websites or Services.  “Personal information” is data that can be used to uniquely identify or contact a single person. Personal information we collect may include your name, phone number, mailing address, e-mail address and payment information, such as credit card number and expiration date.  We may also collect information such as your organization’s name, your title within the organization, industry type and 501(c)(3) status, and other business information about the organization.  We may collect information from you when you use our Websites, such as when you sign up for a Network for Good account, subscribe to our newsletters, register to attend a webinar, or make a donation.

When you submit payment information to us via the Websites, you consent to providing your payment information to us and to our vendors processing the donation to the extent required to provide our Services to you.  When we collect payment information directly from you, we transmit this payment information directly to our vendor.  For donations, we store the final four digits of the card number and the expiration date.

We also collect non-personal information from you passively.  Like most website administrators, we use log files that record information such as Internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, Internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, platform type, date/time stamp, and page navigation. We gather this information to track website visitor movement in the aggregate, and to gather broad demographic information for aggregate use. Our goal in gathering this information is to learn how our customers and the public are using our Services. IP addresses that are recorded by our log files are not linked to personal information.

**Links and Third Party Websites**

The Websites contain links to other sites and in certain circumstances, we use third parties to provide you with certain services as discussed in greater detail in our [Services Agreement](https://www.networkforgood.com/about/network-for-good-services-agreement/) (which governs use by nonprofits who subscribe to our Services) and [Terms & Conditions ](https://www.networkforgood.com/about/terms/)(which govern use by donors, visitors of the Websites, and nonprofit organizations who may receive donations through our Services but do not subscribe). Please be aware that Network for Good is not responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites or companies. We encourage our users to be aware when they leave our site and to read the privacy statements of each and every website that collects personal information. This Privacy Policy applies solely to information collected by our Websites.

**Cookies**

Please see the Special Provisions below in Section 2 and Section 3 for more information on the cookies we use if you are a donor or a nonprofit customer or potential customer.

For all Website users, as you navigate through and interact with our Websites, we may automatically collect certain information about your equipment, browsing actions and patterns, including details of your visits to our Websites, including traffic data, location data, logs, and other communication data and the resources that you access and use on the Websites; information about your computer and internet connection, including your IP address, operating system and browser type; and other information obtained through third party analytics tools, such as Google Analytics.

  * Network for Good uses Google Analytics, a web analytics service provided by Google Inc. (“Google”). Google Analytics uses “cookies”, text files that are stored on your computer, to analyze your use of the Websites. The information generated by the cookie about your use of the Websites (including your shortened IP address) is transmitted to a Google server in the U.S. and stored there. Google will use this information to evaluate your use of the Websites, compile reports on website activity for us, and to provide other services related to the Websites and internet use. Google may also transfer this information to third parties if required by law, or where third parties process these data on behalf of Google. For more information about Google Analytics, or to opt out of Google Analytics, please go to the [Google Analytics Opt Out Settings page](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout).
  * We use cookies in order to bring you more relevant messaging with Google Display and Search Advertising (e.g., Remarketing or Google Display Network Impression Reporting).
  * We use third-party vendors, including Google, in order to show ads on third-party sites across the Internet.
  * Network for Good along with third-party vendors, including Google, use first-party cookies (such as the Google Analytics cookie) and third-party cookies (such as the DoubleClick cookie) together to inform, optimize, and serve ads based on past visits to our Websites and to report how ad impressions, other uses of ad services, and interactions with these ad impressions and ad services are related to visits to the Websites.
  * We use data from Google Analytics Demographics, Interest Reporting, and third-party audience data to help us understand how people find and use our Websites.
  * Visitors can opt-out of Google Analytics for Display Advertising, customize Google Display Network ads using [Google’s Ads Settings page](https://www.google.com/settings/ads).
  * Cookies do not allow the Websites to access personal information that you haven’t already provided to us.
  * Network for Good may use third party analytics services like Crazy Egg’s Analysis Service or FullStory, which provide us with a clearer picture of how you use the Websites, such as where you click on the Websites, non-sensitive text entered into the Websites, and mouse movements.  Your use of the Website is also subject to Crazy Egg’s and FullStory’s privacy policies. You can visit Crazy Egg’s privacy policy at: <https://www.crazyegg.com/privacy> and their opt-out feature on [Crazy Egg’s Opt Out Settings page](https://www.crazyegg.com/opt-out).  You can read FullStory’s privacy policy here: <https://fullstory.com/legal/privacy>.  If you wish to opt out of our use of FullStory with respect to your use of the Websites, you may do so by visiting <https://www.fullstory.com/optout/>.

**Do Not Track Requests; Third Party Tracking**

Network for Good does not currently take actions to respond to Do Not Track signals sent by your web browser because a uniform technological standard has not yet been developed. We continue to review new technologies and may adopt a standard once one is created.  Third parties, other than our vendors (such as our website analytics providers), do not have authorization from us to track which websites you visited prior to and after visiting the Websites.  That said, we cannot control third party tracking and there may be some third party tracking that occurs without our knowledge or consent.

**How We Use Your Information**

If you make donations through Network for Good or are a nonprofit, customer, or potential customer, our use of your personal information will be described in the Special Provisions below.  In addition to such uses, we may use the information we collect in accordance with this Privacy Policy for the following purposes:

  * To provide the Services that you request and to communicate with you regarding such Services;
  * To respond to your inquiries and to contact you about changes to the Websites;
  * To send you notices or our e-Newsletter (if you have signed up to receive it);
  * To notify you of opportunities for future donations;
  * To send you information about our products, Services and other offerings;
  * To provide and maintain the Websites, help diagnose problems with the Websites, and to administer and audit usage of the Websites;
  * For statistical analysis and internal business purposes such as identifying fundraising trends.
  * For any other purposes disclosed at the time the information is collected or to which you consent; and
  * As otherwise specifically described in this Privacy Policy.

**Information You Publicly Post**

If you decide to participate in our Websites’ features, such as online blogs, by posting content, you understand that this information is publicly available.

**Information You Provide to Social Networking Sites**

The Websites allow you to access social networking sites including Facebook®, Twitter®, LinkedIn®, and GooglePlus®.

**How We Share Your Information**

**Complying With the Legal System**

Though Network for Good makes every effort to preserve donor and customer privacy, we may need to disclose personal information when we have a good-faith belief that such action is necessary to comply with a current judicial proceeding, a court order, or legal process served on our organization.  We also may disclose your personal information to third parties if we have reason to believe that disclosing such information is necessary to conduct investigations of possible breaches of law, to cooperate in any legal investigation, or to identify, contact, or bring legal action against someone who may be violating any agreement with us, including our Terms & Conditions.

**Profiles or Accounts**

When you, if a donor, submit your contact information to sign up for a Network for Good Profile, you agree and consent that Network for Good may send you communication relating to our products, events, or recommended charities.  When you, if a nonprofit, submit your organization’s contact information to sign up for an account with Network for Good, you agree and consent that Network for Good may send your organization communication relating to our products, events, or other business information.  Please [contact us](https://www.networkforgood.com/contact/) to opt out of receiving such communication or you may opt out by clicking on the “unsubscribe” link at the bottom of our emails.

**Disclosure or Transfer of Data to Affiliates or Subsidiaries or in Connection with Organization Change**

We may disclose personal information that we collect or you provide to us with our affiliates or subsidiaries that require access to your personal information for business purposes.

We may disclose personal information that we collect or you provide as described in this Privacy Policy to any buyer or other successor in the event of a merger, divestiture, restructuring, reorganization, dissolution, or other sale or transfer of some or all of our assets, whether as a going concern or as part of bankruptcy, liquidation, or similar proceeding, in which personal information held by us about users of our Websites is among the assets transferred.

In the event that Network for Good is involved in a bankruptcy, merger, acquisition, consolidation, change of control, liquidation, reorganization, or sale or transfer of assets, your information may be sold or transferred as part of that transaction. Our obligations in this Privacy Policy will apply to your information as transferred to the new entity.

**Disclosure or Transfer of Data to Third Party Vendors**

We may use third parties to help operate and improve our Websites, assist us in providing products or services to you, to process and collect payments, to provide analytics, or provide tools we embed into our Websites, products, and services. We may share information we have about you with such third parties, solely for their use to provide services to us. Please be aware that such third parties have their own privacy policies, which govern their use of your information. For a full list of such third parties and their privacy policies, please [contact us](https://www.networkforgood.com/contact/).

**Other Terms**

**Transfer of Information**

We are based in the United States of America. Any personal information you provide may be stored and maintained in a secure database in the United States or transferred to a secure database outside the United States. By providing us with your information, you consent to this transfer.

**Children Under the Age of 13**

We do not knowingly collect personal information from children under 13 or knowingly allow such persons to log in to the Websites. If you are under 13, do not use or provide any information on these Websites or on or through any of its features or provide any information about yourself to us, including your name, address, telephone number, e-mail address, or any screen name or user name you may use. If we learn we have collected or received personal information from a child under 13 without verification of parental consent, we will delete that information as soon as practicable. If you believe we might have any information from or about a child under 13, please [contact us](http://www1.networkforgood.org/contact-us).

**Accessing, Correcting and Deleting Your Information**

If you would like to access, modify, correct, or delete your personal information, please [contact us](http://www1.networkforgood.org/contact-us). When you contact us, you may be required to provide us some details to verify your identity in this case. We may not accommodate a request to change or delete information if we believe the change would violate any law or legal requirement, cause the information to be incorrect, or we are unable to verify your identity.  In addition, if you have provided your information to the charity or charities you supported through Network for Good in accordance with this Privacy Policy, you may need to contact that charity instead, if the relevant personal information is only accessible by that charity.  If we have received your information from a third party, we may not be able to modify, correct or delete your information.

**Your California Privacy Rights**

California Civil Code Section § 1798.83 permits users of our Websites that are California residents to request certain information regarding our disclosure of personal information to third parties for their direct marketing purposes. To make such a request, please [contact us](http://www1.networkforgood.org/contact-us). Under Section § 1798.83, we currently do not share any personal information with third parties for their direct marketing purposes.

**Changes to the Policy**

Network for Good periodically reviews and updates this Privacy Policy. If we decide to change this Privacy Policy, we will post those changes to our Websites so our donors and customers are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it. We may also, in our sole discretion, notify you of such changes via our e-Newsletter or email to your email address that we have in our records.  Any updates or changes to this Privacy Policy will become effective upon posting.  By continuing to access or use any of our Websites after those changes become effective, you agree to be bound by the revised Privacy Policy.

### **2\. Special Privacy & Security Provisions for Donors**

Network for Good respects and protects your privacy and will never sell or rent your personal information to other individuals or companies. The information that you provide is used only to complete your donation, provide you with a donation receipt or, upon request, provide you with a donation history. With your permission, your name and contact information will be provided to the charity or charities you supported through Network for Good. If you do not wish share your name and contact information with the charity or charities you supported through Network for Good or you choose to make your donation anonymously, Network for Good will not share your name or contact information. Network for Good provides a field to include an optional dedication with the donation. Network for Good reserves the right in its sole discretion to remove text from this field before it is provided to the designated charity, for example, if Network for Good deems it inappropriate, offensive, or misrepresentative.

When you create an account with Network for Good you may choose to receive your donation records at tax time and occasional email updates on your favorite charities and The Good Card®. If you do not wish to hear from us, simply uncheck the box on the bottom of the billing page, unsubscribe from a mailing using the “unsubscribe” link, or [contact us](http://www1.networkforgood.org/contact-us) directly.

  * Add This Social Sharing: If you use the social sharing features on the Websites to inform a friend about our Websites or Services, you will be asked to provide the friend’s name and email address. Network for Good stores this information for the sole purpose of sending a one-time email and will not add your friend to our mailing list.
  * The Good Card®: If you purchase a Good Card on our Websites, all of your personal information is kept confidential by Network for Good. When the card recipient uses their card to give to charity their personal information is also kept confidential. We do not share the recipient’s information with the charity they choose. The recipient gets the option of letting the purchaser know they have redeemed their card.

**Special note on employee giving:**   Network for Good provides employee giving solutions for partner companies. When Network for Good is processing donations as part of a specific employee giving campaign on the Websites or a page hosted by Network for Good, we do share some donor information (such as name, email address, donation amount), but not credit card or financial information, with the partner company to confirm that the donation was made by a legitimate employee. In these instances, the partner company has disclosed its relationship to Network for Good through its Intranet, website or employee communications prior to the donation being made.

**Special note on corporate partners:**   Network for Good partners with other organizations and companies to enable giving across the Internet. Please be aware that donor information shared through a corporate partner site is accessible by the partner and Network for Good. Network for Good is not responsible for the privacy practices of our partners and any donor information shared through partner sites. Any such information is subject to that partner’s privacy policy.

However, when donations are “Powered by Network for Good,” the donor information shared with recipient charities is subject to Network for Good’s Privacy Policy.  **Special note on charities:**   Each charity has its own policies regarding privacy of donor information. Please contact the charity you contribute to directly to learn about their privacy policies. We will only pass on the information you provide us if you authorize us to do so.

**What information is being shared by Network for Good with the recipient charity?**

When you make a donation via a charity website that subscribes and links to a DonateNow or any Fundraising pages hosted by Network for Good, your full contact information will be shared with that charity.  When you make a donation via the Websites, other Network for Good products, or a partner website that uses Network for Good’s donation processing services, you may be asked what information you wish to be shared with the recipient charity(ies). You may have a choice of: full contact information, name and email address only, or no personal information (anonymous).  Network for Good respects donor privacy and only shares information with donor consent.  For example, when a donor has asked to remain anonymous, no information is shared with the charity – we simply confirm that a donation has been made.

**How can I confirm what donor information was shared by Network for Good with the recipient charity or request corrections?**

If you want to confirm information shared with a recipient charity or change your personal information, please contact our [Customer Support Team](http://www1.networkforgood.org/contact-us), and a Support Specialist will be happy to help you.  If you are looking to get in touch directly with a charity, you can find contact information in our partner [GuideStar](http://www.guidestar.org/)’s database.

**Charitable Solicitation Disclosure**

You can read our Charitable Solicitation Disclosure online [here](http://www1.networkforgood.org/solicitationdisclosure) or at  https://www.networkforgood.com/about/charitable-solicitation-disclosures/

**Complying with Donor Advised Fund Regulations**

Most donations through the Network for Good giving system are processed by the Network for Good Donor Advised Fund (“N4G.ORG”), a section 501(c)(3) nonprofit, donor advised fund, which will distribute your donation to the nonprofit organization that you recommended.  However, some donations made through the Network for Good giving system are processed directly by the nonprofit of your choice and not by N4G.ORG.  When your donation is processed by N4G.ORG, as required by the Internal Revenue Service (“IRS”), N4G.ORG has exclusive legal control over the donations to our donor-advised fund.  All donations are final and may not be refunded.  In the rare event that a charity you have recommended does not satisfy N4G.ORG’s criteria for receiving donations (e.g., it has been classified by the IRS as a disqualified supporting organization, it cannot or does not accept donations, is not recognized by the IRS as a section 501(c)(3) public charity, or is not in good standing with federal and state regulators), N4G.ORG will select an alternate charity to receive your donation funds.

**Cookies**

Network for Good uses “session cookies” while a visitor is making a donation via Network for Good hypertext links, sometimes referred to as donation buttons. “Cookies” are bits of information that are stored by your browser on your hard drive. We use “session cookies” so that we can properly verify a donor’s identity as they move from one donation page to the next. These session cookies are not linked to personal information.

### **3\. Special Privacy & Security Provisions for Nonprofits, Customers, and Potential Customers**

You may choose to register to receive additional information or Services from us. When you register, we request personal information about you such as your name, email address and/or telephone number, and we may ask for other information to enable us to provide a more relevant, personalized service to you. The information you provide may be stored in our databases. We endeavor to limit our requests for personal information to information we believe is minimally necessary to achieve our stated collection purposes.  We may also supplement your profile information with publicly available data, such as zip codes and other demographic information.

We also collect payment information so that we can process one-time and/or recurring fees and to carefully screen organizations for our subscription services to ensure that their programmatic work meets the scope of our vision statement. Applicants fill out an online Application Form, which our customer service staff reviews. We may contact an applicant to verify information. The one-time and recurring fees are processed through a credit card processing company. Nonprofit customers can log into their password protected “My Account” section to update any personal information.

Network for Good offers its own free e-Newsletter that it sends out to nonprofit customers and other interested individuals that includes online fundraising and marketing advice and training opportunities. Subscribers may choose to unsubscribe at any time and unsubscribe information is located at the bottom of each e-Newsletter. Individuals who donate to nonprofits through the Network for Good DonateNow or other Fundraising page service are not subscribed to this e-Newsletter.

When you download any of our content, such as eGuides, or register for one of our webinars, we collect your personal and organizational information such as: name, address, email address, phone number, etc. Webinar registration information is collected through an event registration vendor who shares the information with Network for Good, but the vendor does not retain, share, store, or use personal information for any secondary purposes. Subscribers may choose to unsubscribe at any time and unsubscribe information is located at the bottom of each e-Newsletter or email communication.

**Cookies**

For our nonprofit customers, we use “session cookies” and “persistent cookies” in addition to verifying personal information, so that we can provide secure access to account and donor information. These session cookies are not linked to personal information.

**EventsNow Privacy & Security**

Network for Good’s EventsNow service has its own privacy policy, which can be found here: <https://www.salsalabs.com/privacy-policy>

**Our Terms of Use**

Our Terms of Use are available here: [Our Terms & Conditions](https://www.networkforgood.com/about/terms/)

**Contact Information/Questions**
